A Guide to the Papers of the Virginia Quarterly Review, 1935-1954
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Hyde, John 1935-1939, 20 items (Box 100)
- Hyman, Stanley Edgar 1942-1947, 21 items (Box 100)
- Miscellaneous H 1935-1954, ca. 1250 items (Box 101 and 102)
- Ickes, Harold 1938 July 9, 1 l. (Box 102)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Ickes
- Imbrie, Malcolm 1944, 7 items (Box 102)
- Ingalls, Jeremy 1939 November 10, 1 l. (Box 102)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Ingalls
- Ingersoll and Brennan 1939-1951, 17 items (Box 102)
- Inman, Arthur 1941 January 23, 1 l. (Box 102)
- Institute of Public Relations 1939-1945, 6 items (Box 102)
- Irvine, William 1938-1952, 25 items (Box 102)
- Irwin, Franklin 1941-1942, 5 items (Box 102)
- Isham, Ralph 1942, 5 items (Box 102)
- Ives, Marian 1937-1951, 27 items (Box 102)
- Miscellaneous I 1935-1954, ca. 80 items (Box 102)
- Jackson, Herbert 1929-1937, 16 items (Box 103)
- Jackson, Phyllis 1954 October 27, 1 l. (Box 103)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Jackson
- Jackson, Robert 1951-1954, 7 items (Box 103)
- Jackson, William 1949-1950, 8 items (Box 103)
- Jaeger, Hans 1947 May 20, 2 p. (Box 103)
  ALS, to Virginia Quarterly Review, encl. Clipping
- Jaffe, Louis 1935-1939, 12 items (Box 103)
- Jaffe, Philip 1939, 7 items (Box 103)
- James, Edwin 1949, 2 items (Box 103)
- James, William Cole 1941 March 26, 1 l. (Box 103)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to James
- Jameson, Margaret Storm 1949, 7 items (Box 103)
- Jara, Anibal 1939-1940, 5 items (Box 103)
- Jarrell, Randall 1938-1954, ca. 50 items (Box 103)
- Jeffers, Mr. and Mrs. Robinson 1939-1949, 14 items (Box 103)
- Jenkins, Brooks 1939-1940, 3 items (Box 103)
- Jenkins, William Franklin 1944-1949, 10 items (Box 103)
- Jessup, Philip 1946, 2 items (Box 103)
- Jewell, James n.d., 1 l. (Box 103)
- Jimenez, Mr. and Mrs. Juan Ramon 1938-1939, 4 items (Box 103)
  TL(carbons), Virginia Quarterly Review to Mr. and Mrs. Jimenez
- Joesten, Joachim 1941-1954, ca. 50 items (Box 103)
- Johns, Jay 1935-1939, 15 items (Box 103)
- Johnson, Alvin 1937 December 18, 1 l. (Box 103)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Johnson
- Johnson, Cary 1936-1954, 21 items (Box 103)
- Johnson, Geoffrey 1936-1954, 30 items (Box 103)
- Johnson, Gerald 1935-1950, ca. 100 items (Box 103)
- Johnson, Guy 1948, 11 items (Box 103)
- Johnson, Hewlett 1940-1941, 5 items (Box 103)
- Johnson, Hugh 1935-1936, 3 items (Box 103)
- Johnson, Joseph 1950, 2 items (Box 103)
- Johnson, Josephine 1938-1954, ca. 50 items (Box 103)
- Johnson, Walter 1949-1954, 20 items (Box 103)
- Johnston, Mary 1926 November 19, 1 l. (Box 103)
- Johnston, Summerfield 1924, 17 items (Box 103)
- Jones, Howard Mumford 1936-1954, 7 items (Box 103)
- Jones, Theodore 1941, 2 items (Box 103)
- Jones, Thomas Catesby 1935-1940, 27 items (Box 103)
- Jones, Turner 1935-1939, 16 items (Box 103)
- Jorgensen, Christine 1953 January 30, 1 l. (Box 103)
  Printed LS, to Virginia Quarterly Review
- Joseph, J. Calder 1937-1938, 9 items (Box 103)
- Joseph, Nannine 1936-1954, ca. 60 items (Box 103)
- Josephson, Matthew 1937-1949, ca. 50 items (Box 103)
- Joyce, James 1938 July 18, 1 l. (Box 103)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Joyce
- Miscellaneous J 1935-1954, ca. 400 items (Box 104)
- Kallem, Horace 1937-1938, 3 items (Box 104)
- Kandahl, Torolv 1942-1943, 4 items (Box 104)
- Karpeles, Maud 1950-1951, 6 items (Box 104)
- Karpovich, Michael 1953, 3 items (Box 104)
- Kauder, Emil 1949-1950, 14 items (Box 104)
- Kaffmann, Stanley 1937-1950, 18 items (Box 104)
- Kayden, Eugene 1936-1946, ca. 75 items (Box 104)
- Kazin, Alfred 1940-1944, ca. 75 items (Box 104)
- Keenan, D'Elbert 1938, 11 items (Box 104)
- Kefauver, Estes 1949-1950, 11 items (Box 104)
- Keith, Joseph Joel 1947-1953, 15 items (Box 104)
- Kendrick, Benjamin 1937, 4 items (Box 104)
- Kennan, George 1947-1950, 12 items (Box 104)
- Kent, Frank 1936, 3 items (Box 104)
- Kent, Louis 1947-1948, 6 items (Box 104)
- Kent, Sherman 1949, 3 items (Box 104)
- Kernan, W.F. 1942-1948, 24 items (Box 104)
- Kernig, Walter 1943 January 4, 1 l. (Box 104)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Kernig
- Key, V.O. 1950-1954, ca. 50 items (Box 104)
- Keynes, John Maynard 1937-1938, 2 items (Box 104)
- Key-Smith, Francis 1938-1939, 15 items (Box 104)
- Kiker, Douglas 1951-1954, 4 items (Box 104)
- Kilmer, Kenton 1936 May 15, 1 l. (Box 104)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Kilmer
- Kilpatrick, Carroll 1935-1954, ca. 60 items (Box 104)
- Kimball, Fiske 1932-1946, 12 items (Box 105)
- Kimball, Marie 1937-1946, ca. 60 items (Box 105)
- King, Eleanor 1945-1954, ca. 50 items (Box 105)
- King, William 1935 June 15, 1 l. (Box 105)
- Kinsolving, Arthur 1941-1945, 19 items (Box 105)
- Kirby, John 1946-1954, ca. 100 items (Box 105)
- Kirk, Russell 1945-1952, 11 items (Box 105)
- Klausner, Bertha 1948-1953, 11 items (Box 105)
- Knollenberg, Bernhard 1941, 5 items (Box 105)
- Alfred A. Knopf, Inc. 1926-1952, ca. 100 items (Box 105)
- Knox, Bernard 1954, 11 items (Box 105)
- Knox, Frank 1942, 2 items (Box 105)
- Koch, Adrienne 1940-1954, 12 items (Box 105)
- Kohler, Dayton 1936-1941, 14 items (Box 105)
- Kraus, Hans Felix 1939-1942, 16 items (Box 105)
- Kreymborg, Alfred 1940-1953, 6 items (Box 105)
- Kroll, Ernest 1945-1954, 18 items (Box 105)
- Krutch, Joseph Wood 1938-1954, ca. 50 items (Box 105)
- Krzyzanowski, Ludwig 1942, 7 items (Box 105)
- Miscellaneous K 1935-1954, ca. 700 items (Box 105 & 106)
- Labaree, Leonard 1938-1954, 34 items (Box 106)
- Lafitte-Cyon, Francoise 1940, 8 items (Box 106)
- LaFollette, Robert 1935-1936, 2 items (Box 106)
- Lagden, Mervyn 1951-1953, 13 items (Box 106)
- LaGuardia, Fiorello 1939, 5 items (Box 106)
- Lamont, Corliss 1940-1950, 21 items (Box 106)
- Lamont, Thomas 1938-1939, 4 items (Box 106)
- Lamott, Willis Church 1946-1947, 18 items (Box 106)
- Landis, James 1938-1939, 14 items (Box 106)
- Landon, Alfred 1936 December 15, 1 l. (Box 106)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Landon
- Langdon, John 1941-1954, 7 items (Box 106)
- Langer, William 1953, 3 items (Box 106)
- Langford, Gerald 1940-1950, 20 items (Box 106)
- Lape, Fred 1937-1953, 20 items (Box 106)
- Larsson, Raymond 1938, 2 items (Box 106)
- Lasker, Bruno 1940-1946, 28 items (Box 106)
- Laski, Harold 1937-1945, 5 items (Box 106)
- Lattimore, Owen 1939-1950, ca. 50 items (Box 106)
- Lattimore, Richmond 1939-1950, 2 items (Box 106)
  TL(carbons), Virginia Quarterly Review to Lattimore
- Laurence, Frank 1951-1952, 8 items (Box 106)
- Lauterbach, Richard 1947, 4 items (Box 106)
- Laves, Walter 1951, 15 items (Box 106)
- Lawlor, John 1953-1954, 13 items (Box 106)
- Larwrence, David 1936 December 14, 1 l. (Box 106)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Lawrence
- Lawrence, Frieda 1938-1940, ca. 50 items (Box 107)
- League of American Writers 1938-1939, 11 items (Box 107)
- Leary, Lewis 1953-1954, 5 items (Box 107)
- LeDoux, Burton 1940-1944, ca. 60 items (Box 107)
- Lee, Lawrence 1927-1954, ca. 150 items (Box 107)
- Leeper, Robert 1946 June 19, 1 l. (Box 107)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Leeper
- Lehman, Edwin 1941, 4 items (Box 107)
- Leiserson, William 1946, 2 items (Box 107)
- Leishman, James Blair 1953, 5 items (Box 107)
- Leitch, Mary Sinton 1936-1952, 11 items (Box 107)
- Lenniger, August 1940-1945, 19 items (Box 107)
- Leopold, Aldo 1940-1941, 7 items (Box 107)
- Lepawsky, Albert 1949-1953, 13 items (Box 107)
- Lerner, Max 1936-1953, ca. 100 items (Box 107)
- Lescaze, William 1938-1939, 21 items (Box 107)
- Leslie, William 1952-1953, 11 items (Box 107)
- Lesser, Simon 1947-1953, 32 items (Box 107)
- Lester, Richard 1940-1954, ca. 50 items (Box 107)
- Levin, Harry 1938-1952, 5 items (Box 107)
- Levy, Marion 1949-1950, 16 items (Box 107)
- Lewis, Cecil Day 1947, 5 items (Box 107)
- Lewis, David 1935, 5 items (Box 107)
- Lewis, Ivey 1937 April 13, 1 l. (Box 107)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Lewis
- Lewis, John Llewellyn, Representatives of 1939, 26 items (Box 108)
- Lewis, Richard 1951, 3 items (Box 108)
- Lewis, Sinclair 1930 January 12, 1 l. (Box 108)
- Lewis, Wilmarth 1945-1950, 20 items (Box 108)
- Lewis, Willmott 1947 April 1, 1 l. (Box 108)
- Ley, Willy 1940-1943, 10 items (Box 108)
- Liddell Hart, Basil Henry 1937-1953, 14 items (Box 108)
- Lieber, Maxim 1936-1951, ca. 250 items (Box 108)
- Lieberman, Elias 1937 June 14, 1 l. (Box 108)
- Lilienthal, David 1939-1940, 7 items (Box 108)
- Lindbergh, Anne Morrow 1940 March 29, 1 l. (Box 108)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Lindbergh
- Lindley, Ernest 1936-1954, ca. 60 items (Box 108)
- Lindsay, A.D. 1945-1946, 8 items (Box 108)
- Lindsay, Michael 1947, 10 items (Box 108)
- Lineaweaver, Marion 1944-1953, 13 items (Box 108)
- Linebarger, Paul 1945-1954, 15 items (Box 108)
- Linke, Lilo 1939-1940, 15 items (Box 108)
- J. B. Lippincott Company 1931-1946, 11 items (Box 108)
- Lippman, Walter 1935-1954, 16 items (Box 108)
- Little, Brown, and Company 1926-1953, 43 items (Box 109)
- Livingstone, Tristram 1936-1939, ca. 60 items (Box 109)
- Lloyd George, David, Representative of 1939, 2 items (Box 109)
- Logan, John 1953-1954, 5 items (Box 109)
- Long, Breckinridge 1929-1935, 18 items (Box 109)
- Longmans, Green and Company 1926-1940, 33 items (Box 109)
- Lorentz, Pare 1939, 15 items (Box 109)
- Lovejoy, Arthur 1943-1952, 3 items (Box 109)
- Lovett, Robert Morss 1937-1946, 19 items (Box 109)
- Lowe, Robert Liddell 1937-1938, 14 items (Box 109)
- Lowell, Robert 1946-1947, 5 items (Box 109)
- Lubin, Isador 1939, 8 items (Box 109)
- Lucas, Frank Laurence 1937, 3 items (Box 109)
- Lull, Roderick 1946-1948, 7 items (Box 109)
- Lumpkin, Grace 1953, 2 items (Box 109)
- Lundberg, Ferdinand 1940, 6 items (Box 109)
- Lupton, Cartter 1924-1939, ca. 50 items (Box 109)
- Lyman, David 1939-1942, 6 items (Box 109)
- Lyman, Lauren 1942 June 25, 1 l. (Box 109)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Lyman
- Lytle, Andrew 1937-1947, 4 items (Box 109)
- Miscellaneous L 1935-1954, ca. 1100 items (Box 109 & 110)
- M C A Management, Ltd. 1946-1951, ca. 200 items (Box 111)
- Maas, Willard 1937-1938, 12 items (Box 111)
- Mabon, Mr. and Mrs. Scott 1938-1939, 21 items (Box 111)
- McBride, Harry Alexander 1936 December 22, 1 l. (Box 111)
- McCall, Monica 1940-1954, ca. 50 items (Box 111)
- McCarthy, John Russell, 7 items (Box 111)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to McCarthy
- McCleary, Dorothy 1953, 4 items (Box 111)
- McCloy, John 1954, 2 items (Box 111)
- McCord, David 1936-1939, 11 items (Box 111)
- McCormick, Anne O'Hare 1942, 2 items (Box 111)
- McCullers, Carson 1938-1940, 3 items (Box 111)
- MacDonald, Alexander 1939-1940, 4 items (Box 111)
- McDonald, Angus 1941, 2 items (Box 111)
- McDonald, Edward 1940, 9 items (Box 111)
- McDonald, Jemes 1938 July 12, 1 l. (Box 111)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to McDonald
- McDowell, Tremaine 1949, 8 items (Box 111)
- McGill, Ralph 1945-1953, 8 items (Box 111)
- McIntosh and Otis, Inc. 1939-1954 (Box 111)
- Mavis McIntosh-Elizabeth McKee 1944-1954, ca. 100 items (Box 111)
- McIntosh, McKee, and Batchelder 1949, 3 items (Box 111)
- MacIntyre, Carlyle 1937-1940, ca. 50 items (Box 111)
- McIntyre, Marvin, Representative of 1938, 2 items (Box 111)
- McKay, Donald 1952-1953, 5 items (Box 111)
- McKee and Batchelder 1938-1949, 16 items (Box 111)
- McKeogh and Boyd 1937-1942, 16 items (Box 111)
- McKeon, Richard 1952-1953, 9 items (Box 111)
- McLean, Frank 1939-1940, 8 items (Box 111)
- MacLeish, Archibald 1938-1954, 27 items (Box 111)
- Maclennan, R.D. 1952-1953, 10 items (Box 111)
- Macleod, Norman 1937-1938, 3 items (Box 111)
  TL(carbons), Virginia Quarterly Review to Macleod
- McLuhan, Marshall 1947, 2 items (Box 111)
- MacMahon, Caroline 1944-1945, 17 items (Box 111)
- Macmillan Company 1926-1951, ca. 150 items (Box 111)
- McNaughton, John 1929-1932, 6 items (Box 111)
  TL(carbons), Virginia Quarterly Review to MacNaughton
- MacNeice, Louis 1939-1948, 3 items (Box 111)
  TL(carbons), Virginia Quarterly Review to MacNeice
- McNutt, Paul 1939-1940, 12 items (Box 111)
- McVeigh, Charles 1939-1954, 5 items (Box 111)
- Madison, Charles 1939-1954, ca. 50 items (Box 112)
- Maggs, Douglas 1953, 2 items (Box 112)
- Maisel, Edward 1939-1941, 15 items (Box 112)
- Malik, Charles 1954, 15 items (Box 112)
- Mallan, Lloyd 1939-1953, ca. 50 items (Box 112)
- Mallet, Robert 1938, 2 items (Box 112)
- Mallet, Marcus 1951, 2 items (Box 112)
- Mallon, Paul 1936-1938, 4 items (Box 112)
- Malone, Dumas 1936-1951, ca. 60 items (Box 112)
- Maltz, Albert 1942 February 3, 1 l. (Box 112)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Maltz
- Mangan, Sherry 1936-1938, 2 items (Box 112)
  TL(carbons), Virginia Quarterly Review to Mangan
- Mann, Thomas 1938-1941, 18 items (Box 112)
- Maritain, Jacques 1938-1944, 13 items (Box 112)
- Marquand, John P. 1952, 3 items (Box 112)
- Marshall, Lenore 1937-1952, 26 items (Box 112)
- Marshall, Snowden 1930-1939, 9 items (Box 112)
- Martin, David 1940, 6 items (Box 112)
- Martin, Kingsley 1949 March 9, 1 l. (Box 112)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Martin
- Masefield, John 1939, 2 items (Box 112)
- Mason, Alpheus Thomas 1937-1950, 18 items (Box 112)
- Mason, Daniel Gregory 1936-1952, 38 items (Box 112)
- Mason, Edward 1949-1952, 5 items (Box 112)
- Mason, Lucy Randolph 1938-1941, ca. 50 items (Box 112)
- Massie, Susanne 1935-1939, 8 items (Box 112)
- Masur, Gerhard 1950-1954, 25 items (Box 112)
- Mathews, Joseph 1944, 13 items (Box 112)
- Matthews, Herbert 1947-1953, 33 items (Box 112)
- Matthiessen, Francis Otto 1936-1947, 8 items (Box 112)
- Sister Maura 1950 March 8, 1 l. (Box 112)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Maura
- Maury, Richmond 1938-1941, 18 items (Box 112)
- Maverick, Maury 1938-1939, 19 items (Box 112)
- Maxwell, Gilbert 1938-1951, 12 items (Box 112)
- May, James Boyer 1938-1954, 30 items (Box 112)
- Mayer, Frederick 1942-1950, 14 items (Box 112)
- Mayhall, Jane 1946-1949, 17 items (Box 112)
- Maynard, Theodore 1937-1953, 15 items (Box 112)
- Mayo, Barbara Smith 1941-1946, 6 items (Box 112)
- Mayo, Bernard 1943-1952, 14 items (Box 112)
- Meacham, Harry 1953, 2 items (Box 113)
- Meacham, William Shands 1951-1954, 23 items (Box 113)
- Mead, Margaret 1952-1953, 10 items (Box 113)
- Means, Gardiner 1941-1943, 16 items (Box 113)
- Means, James Howard 1938, 2 items (Box 113)
- Mears, Helen 1949-1953, 8 items (Box 113)
- Mechling, Tom 1946, 10 items (Box 113)
- Meiklejohn, Alexander 1937-1952, 6 items (Box 113)
- Mellquist, Jerome 1940-1952, 33 items (Box 113)
- Memminger, Christopher Gustavus 1924-1928, 5 items (Box 113)
  5 TLS, to Virginia Quarterly Review
- Mencken, Henry Louis 1945, 2 items (Box 113)
- Mendizabal, Miguel de 1939-1940, 10 items (Box 113)
- Menninger, Karl 1940-1943, 20 items (Box 113)
- Mercer, Caroline 1942, 2 items (Box 113)
- Meredith, Scott 1946-1954, 11 items (Box 113)
- Merrell, Marion 1938-1939, 11 items (Box 113)
- Merriam, Eve 1940-1949, 10 items (Box 113)
- Merrick, Elliott 1945 November 12, 1 l. (Box 113)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Merrick
- Merrill, James 1949 October 14, 1 l. (Box 113)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Merrill
- Merwin, W.S. 1948-1952, 12 items (Box 113)
- Metcalf, Jesse 1936, 2 items (Box 113)
- Metcalf, John Calvin 1937-1947, 25 items (Box 113)
- Metzdorf, Robert 1940, 2 items (Box 113)
- Mexican Embassy 1938, 18 items (Box 113)
- Meyer, Henry Cord 1953-1954, 7 items (Box 113)
- Micaud, Charles 1947-1950, 11 items (Box 113)
- Michael, Franz 1944, 8 items (Box 113)
- Michie, A. R. 1939-1940, 2 items (Box 113)
  TL(carbons), Virginia Quarterly Review to Michie
- Miles, Josephine 1938-1947, 4 items (Box 113)
- Millay, Edna St. Vincent 1938 December 27, 1 l. (Box 113)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Millay
- Miller, Francis Pickens 1938-1950, 20 items (Box 113)
- Miller, Helen Hill 1936-1954, ca. 150 items (Box 113)
- Miller, Henry 1936-1939, 4 items (Box 113)
- Miller, Perry 1947-1953, 23 items (Box 113)
- Millis, Walter 1935-1954, ca. 100 items (Box 113)
- Mills, Lennox 1949-1950, 20 items (Box 113)
- Milton, George Fort 1930-1940, 13 items (Box 113)
- Mims, Edwin 1941-1952, 14 items (Box 113)
- Minelli, Pablo 1939-1940, 10 items (Box 113)
- Minor, Benjamin 1934-1939, 37 items (Box 113)
- Minton, Sherman 1938, 2 items (Box 113)
- Mitchell, Broadus 1936-1953, ca. 50 items (Box 113)
- Mitchell, Kate 1943, 2 items (Box 113)
- Mitchell, Margaret 1941 March 6, 1 l. (Box 113)
- Mittell, Sherman 1936-1940, 16 items (Box 113)
- The Modern Group, Inc. 1937-1938, 17 items (Box 114)
- Moffatt, Lucius Gaston 1941-1943, 5 items (Box 114)
- Molotov, Vjacheslav 1939 August 14, 1 l. (Box 114)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Molotov
- Monroe, Elizabeth 1951-1952, 14 items (Box 114)
- Montague, Margaret Prescott 1937-1941, 7 items (Box 114)
- Moon, Bulklin 1936 July 13, 1 l. (Box 114)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Moon
- Moore, John Bassett 1940-1942, 24 items (Box 114)
- Moore, Merrill 1937, 9 items (Box 114)
- Moore, Robert Walton 1935-1936, 27 items (Box 114)
- Moorehead, Alan 1950, 3 items (Box 114)
- Moos, Malcolm 1944-1947, 22 items (Box 114)
- More, Paul 1924 January 6, 1 l. (Box 114)
- Morgan, Edmund 1947-1952, 8 items (Box 114)
- Morgan, Edwin 1948-1954, 8 items (Box 114)
- Morison, Samuel Eliot 1949, 2 items (Box 114)
- Morize, André 1938, 9 items (Box 114)
- Morley, Christopher 1935-1936, 3 items (Box 114)
  TL(carbons), Virginia Quarterly Review to Morley
- Morley, Felix 1935-1953, 7 items (Box 114)
- Morris, Arthur 1924-1940, 25 items (Box 114)
- William Morris Agency 1938-1954, ca. 50 items (Box 114)
- Morrison, Theodore 1936-1952, ca. 50 items (Box 114)
- William Morrow and Co. 1926-1942, 20 items (Box 114)
- Morse, Stearns 1943-1953, 8 items (Box 114)
- Morse, Wayne 1951, 4 items (Box 114)
- Morton, David 1939-1952, ca. 50 items (Box 114)
- Mosely, Philip 1953, 2 items (Box 114)
- Moss, Howard 1951-1954, 5 items (Box 114)
- Mowrer, Edgar 1936-1940, 19 items (Box 114)
- Mowrer, Lillian 1943, 3 items (Box 114)
- Muir, Edwin 1940-1949, 10 items (Box 114)
- Muller, Herbert 1937-1952, ca. 50 items (Box 114)
- Mumford, Beverley 1929-1931, 5 items (Box 114)
- Mumford, Lewis 1938-1954, 29 items (Box 114)
- Muni, Paul 1940 April 10, 1 l. (Box 114)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Muni
- Munos-Marin, Luis 1939 December 27, 1 l. (Box 114)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Munos-Marin
- Munson, Gorham 1938-1942, 9 items (Box 114)
- Murchison, Claudius 1936-1944, 7 items (Box 114)
- Murdock, Kenneth 1946-1948, 10 items (Box 114)
- Murphy, Frank 1939-1940, 20 items (Box 114)
- Murray, Chalmers 1951 December 24, 1 l. (Box 114)
- Murray, Philip 1939-1941, 18 items (Box 114)
- Myers, Walter 1936-1951, ca. 60 items (Box 114)
- Myrdal, Gunnar 1947, 3 items (Box 114)
- Miscellaneous M 1935-1954, ca. 2000 items (Box 115 & 116)
- N.A.A.C.P. 1948, 4 items (Box 117)
- Nagel, Ernest 1937 December 18, 1 l. (Box 117)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Nagel
- The Nation 1936-1942, 15 items (Box 117)
- National Broadcasting Company 1941, 2 items (Box 117)
- Neal, Harry Edward 1946 December 28, 1 l. (Box 117)
- Neatrour, Henriette 1952-1954, 20 items (Box 117)
- Neff, Emery 1949, 3 items (Box 117)
- Negrin, Juan 1938-1939, 5 items (Box 117)
- Nehru, Jawaharlal 1939, 4 items (Box 117)
- Nehru, Pandit 1938 August 1, 1 l. (Box 117)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Nehru
- Neider, Charles 1941-1948, ca. 50 items (Box 117)
- Nelms, Mrs. Haywood 1942, 2 items (Box 117)
- Nerber, John 1945, 2 items (Box 117)
- Neumann, Sigmund 1938-1951, ca. 60 items (Box 117)
- Nevins, Allan 1943-1952, 22 items (Box 117)
- New Directions 1941-1951, 22 items (Box 117)
- The New Republic 1936-1945, 10 items (Box 117)
- New York Herald-Tribune 1936, 5 items (Box 117)
- New York Trust Company 1931-1934, 18 items (Box 117)
- New Zealand Legation 1946-1948, 6 items (Box 117)
- Newcomb, John Lloyd 1931-1943, ca. 50 items (Box 117)
- Newman, Carol, Jr. 1941-1942, 9 items (Box 117)
- Newman, James 1941 April 22, 1 l. (Box 117)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Newman
- Nicholas, Georgia 1942-1947, 15 items (Box 117)
  TL(carbons), Virginia Quarterly Review to Nicholas
- Nichols, Roy 1950-1952, 16 items (Box 117)
- Niebuhr, Reinhold 1937-1953, ca. 50 items (Box 117)
- Nims, John Frederick 1942, 2 items (Box 117)
- Nixon, H.C. 1936-1954, ca. 50 items (Box 117)
- Nock, Albert Jay 1936-1943, 4 items (Box 117)
- Norfleet, Fillmore 1939, 2 items (Box 117)
- Norman, Herbert 1938-1940, 19 items (Box 117)
- Norris, George 1935-1939, 3 items (Box 117)
- University of North Carolina Press 1926-1946, 28 items (Box 117)
- Northrop, Filmer Stuart Cuckow 1947-1954, 6 items (Box 117)
- Norton, Daniel 1942-1949, 24 items (Box 117)
- Norton, Henry 1944 September 14, 1 l. (Box 117)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Norton
- W.W. Norton and Company 1926-1950, ca. 50 items (Box 117)
- Norwood, Hayden 1944, 6 items (Box 117)
- Nourse, Edwin 1943, 2 items (Box 117)
- Nowell, Elizabeth 1935-1954, ca. 200 items (Box 117)
- Noyes, Humphrey 1944-1945, 7 items (Box 118)
- Miscellaneous N 1935-1954, ca. 450 items (Box 118)
  Miscellaneous authors. Correspondence with Virginia Quarterly Review
- Ober, Harold 1944-1952, 11 items (Box 118)
- O'Brien, Edward 1935-1941, 9 items (Box 118)
- O'Casey, Sean 1939-1940, 16 items (Box 118)
- O'Conor, Norreys Jephson 1936-1953, 10 items (Box 118)
- Odets, Clifford 1939 October 17, 1 l. (Box 118)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Odets
- O'Donnell, George Marion 1936-1945, 36 items (Box 118)
- O'Donnell, William 1949, 8 items (Box 118)
- Odum, Howard 1939-1952, 15 items (Box 118)
- O'Faolain, Sean 1938-1952, 26 items (Box 118)
- Ogden, Rollo 1934-1936, 4 items (Box 118)
  TL(carbons), Virginia Quarterly Review to Ogden
- Oi, Atsushi 1952 April 5, 1 l. (Box 118)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Oi
- Old, Herbert 1939-1954, 8 items (Box 118)
- Oldest, Writers' Service 1937-1954, ca. 50 items (Box 118)
- Olson, Elder 1951-1954, 9 items (Box 118)
- Olson, Lawrence 1937-1947, 14 items (Box 118)
- O'Mahoney, Joseph 1938 July 16, 1 l. (Box 118)
- O'Neill, Eugene 1939 October 16, 1 l. (Box 118)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to O'Neill
- Oppenheimer, J. Robert 1953, 2 items (Box 118)
  TL(carbons), Virginia Quarterly Review to Oppenheimer
- Orrick, James 1939-1942, 28 items (Box 118)
- Osgood, Charles 1943, 2 items (Box 118)
- Ostrom, John 1949, 3 items (Box 118)
- Owen, Harry Goddard 1937 June 24, 1 l. (Box 118)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Owen
- Owens, Hamilton 1936, 4 items (Box 118)
- Owsley, Frank 1937-1951, ca. 50 items (Box 119)
- Oxford University Press 1926-1952, ca. 50 items (Box 119)
- Miscellaneous O 1935-1954, ca. 300 items (Box 119)
- Pach, Walter 1935-1952, ca. 50 items (Box 119)
- Padover, Saul 1954, 10 items (Box 119)
- Page, Charles 1952, 12 items (Box 119)
- Pait, James 1941, 3 items (Box 119)
- Panofsky, Erwin 1948, 2 items (Box 119)
- Pargellis, Stanley 1951, 2 items (Box 119)
- Parks, Edd Winfield 1936-1954, ca. 50 items (Box 119)
- Parrish, Stephen 1952, 10 items (Box 119)
- Parsons, Alice Beal 1948, 2 items (Box 119)
- Parsons, Coleman 1947-1952, 36 items (Box 119)
- Parsons, Elizabeth 1952, 3 items (Box 119)
- Parsons, Elsie Clews 1940, 8 items (Box 119)
- Patchen, Kenneth 1936-1938, 5 items (Box 119)
- Patrick, Max 1950 March 1, 1 l. (Box 119)
  TL(carbon), Virginia Quarterly Review to Patrick
- Patterson, Frances Taylor 1936-1951, 31 items (Box 119)
- Pearson, Drew, Secretary of 1938, 6 items (Box 119)
- Pearson, Norman Holmes 1948-1953, 15 items (Box 119)
- Peattie, Roderick 1943, 5 items (Box 119)
- Peck, William 1937-1941, 18 items (Box 119)
- Peden, William 1940-1954, 27 items (Box 119)
- Peery, George 1936 December 12, 1 l. (Box 119)
- Peffer, Nathaniel 1944-1953, 39 items (Box 119)